Sometimes in life there are lists that you do not want to change.
Maybe it's a list of your favorite people.
Maybe it's a list of your favorite restaurants.
Maybe it's a list of your favorite movies.
Whatever it may be, sometimes lists shouldn't change.
Now, at the moment, you can see Alice can change very easily, and it's very handy.
And there are lots of reasons why we want to do that.
But what if we don't want Alice to change regardless?
Okay, in Python, that list that cannot change is called a tuple or tuple.
People pronounce it differently.
I'm going to go with tuple tuple because it rhymes with couple.
Yeah easier to remember.
Okay.
So this unchanging list is actually quite easy to change from a changing list.
So in order to make this a tuple, all I'm doing is I am putting in brackets instead of square brackets.
Now what this means.
This means that no matter what, I cannot change this list.
I cannot add a name.
I cannot change a name.
Uh, it.
Once it's created, it's a solid list.
So those people are coming to the party.
They're my best friends.
So before where?
This program is exactly the same as we had it before we changed this, uh, name, Sarah, to the name
that the user inputted.
So now we're going to try that again.
Run the same program, but now using a tuple.
So let's re tapping clear.
And straight away it's going to give you an error saying tuple object does not support item assignment.
So what that means is basically in simple terms the list cannot be changed.
Yeah that's what it means in English.
Isn't it beautiful tuple object does not support item assignment in English.
It means you can't change this list.
Dude, it's a solid stuck list.
The reason you would want to do this is basically to stop yourself from making silly mistakes.
So if I had had this as a list with the square brackets, but I didn't want to change it, it was something
that was important.
It was something that stayed the same throughout the whole program.
And somehow I made a silly mistake and I did get changed.
And you run your program and suddenly it's not doing what you wanted to do, and you don't understand
why.
And the reason is because something was changed that wasn't meant to change.
But if I had in the beginning defined it as being a tuple, then as soon as I try to change it somewhere
later in the program, it wouldn't let me.
It would throw that error saying, sorry, you can't change this.
Classic example would be you wanted to create a list that had the the months of the year.
So January, February, March, they don't change.
They always the same months of the year that would be created rather than just as a list but as a tuple.
And so you could then easily print out uh, month 12, month 11, etc. by referencing the right item
in the tuple.
Okay, so that was tuples.
And they are solid lists.
Solid lists.